Barbie and the Magic of Pegasus is a animation, family,
romance film directed by Greg Richardson.
Princess Annika escapes the clutches of the evil wizard, explores the wonders of Cloud Kingdom, and teams up with a magnificent winged horse
- who turns out to be her sister, Princess Brietta - to defeat the wizard and break the spells that imprisoned her family.
Princess Annika / Troll / Wife #3 (voice), played by Kelly Sheridan.
Shiver / Queen / Rayla The Cloud Queen / Troll / Wife #1
/ Eric (voice), played by Kathleen Barr.
Brietta / Troll / Wife #2 (voice), played by Lalainia Lindbjerg.
Wenlock (voice), played by Colin Murdock.
Aidan (voice), played by Mark Hildreth.
Ferris / Aidan's Father (voice), played by Brian Drummond.
Barbie and the Magic of Pegasus is a 2005 animated fantasy adventure film directed by Greg Richardson (in his
feature directorial debut) and produced by Mattel Entertainment with Mainframe Entertainment.
It first premiered on Nickelodeon on September 18, 2005, and it was
released later to VHS/DVD on September 20, 2005.
The sixth entry in the Barbie film series, it is the second to feature an original story and the first
not to be based on previous material, as well as the only film to be released in 3D.
It follows the story of Princess Annika, who has to save her parents
after an evil wizard named Wenlock turns them to stone.
Kelly Sheridan reprised her role for Barbie's character and Brie Larson
recorded a song titled "Hope Has Wings" for the film.
The film explores themes of princess, magic,
flying horse, pegasus, based on toy.
The tone is emotional.